Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Information Center Records, 1901-2005 and undated RL.11121
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Information Center Records
1901-2005 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11121
90.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The Chicago Office opened in 1891. The Information Center served as a corporate research library and reference center for the agency.
Arrangement
Arranged into the following series: Administrative Files; Advertising; Research Reports; Special Markets Reports; and Oversize Materials.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Information Center Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001-2004.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center Collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company Information Center Records; J. Walter Thompson Company Chicago Office Information Center Vertical Files; J. Walter Thompson Company Information Center Vertical Files; Douglass Alligood Records.
Collection Overview
Collection and includes memoranda, clippings, research reports and other materials. Subjects addressed include contests, free-standing advertising inserts, coupons and other promotions, marketing of a variety of products including tobacco, hair care and other toiletries, foods including soy protein meat substitutes. Demographic research topics include marketing to children and youth, African Americans, Hispanic Americans, Asian Americans, older consumers, baby boom generation and women. Companies represented include Procter & Gamble, Andrew Jergens, Aunt Jemima and Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States; African American consumers; Asian American consumers; Hispanic American consumers; Baby boom generation -- United States; Advertising and youth; Demographic surveys; Market surveys -- United States; Women consumers -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Administrative Files, 1987-1990; 1
  - LTI Clipping Service, 1987-1988; 11 folders (Box 1)
  - Memos, 1989; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Memos, 1989-1990; 19 folders (Box 2)
  - Memos, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Office move to 900 N. Michigan, 1989 (Box 3)
- Advertising, 1974-1992; 2
  - Contests, 1974-1981; 8 folders (Box 3)
  - Contests, 1981-1988; 10 folders (Box 4)
  - Family Circle, 1989; 7 folders (Box 5)
  - Free-standing inserts, 1985; 10 folders (Box 6)
  - Free-standing inserts, 1985-1987; 10 folders (Box 7)
  - Free-standing inserts, 1987-1988; 12 folders (Box 8)
  - Free-standing inserts, 1988-1989; 10 folders (Box 9)
  - Free-standing inserts, 1989; 11 folders (Box 10)
  - Free-standing inserts, 1989-1990; 11 folders (Box 11)
  - Free-standing inserts, 1990-1991; 13 folders (Box 12)
  - Free-standing inserts, 1991-1992; 10 folders (Box 13)
  - Free-standing inserts, 1992; 9 folders (Box 14)
  - Good Housekeeping, 1989; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 14)
  - Premiums, 1974-1977; 8 folders (Box 15)
  - Premiums, 1981-1985; 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Special offers, 1974-1977; 5 folders (Box 16)
  - Special offers, 1977-1981; 8 folders (Box 17)
  - Special offers, 1981; 9 folders (Box 18)
  - Special offers, 1981-1982; 9 folders (Box 19)
  - Special offers, 1982; 10 folders (Box 20)
  - Special offers, 1982-1983; 8 folders (Box 21)
  - Special offers, 1983; 8 folders (Box 22)
- Research Reports, 1977-1998; 3
  - Four Faces of the American Family (Parents Magazine), 1990 (Box 25)
  - Media at the Millennium (Turner), 1998 (Box 25)
  - Study of Media Involvement 7 (Magazine Publishers Association), 1996 (Box 25)
  - Test Marketing Guide Book vol. 1, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Test Marketing Guide Book vol. 2, 1988 (Box 26)
  - Understanding Buyer Behavior 2: The Role of Information, 1977 (Box 26)
  - Understanding Buyer Behavior 3: Brand Loyalty, 1978 (Box 26)
- Special Markets Reports, 1973-1998 and undated; 4
  - African Americans--Advertising to the Black Consumers, 1979 (Box 26)
  - African Americans--Listerine Antiseptic Black Media Effort, 1984 (Box 26)
  - African Americans--Listerine Antiseptic Revised 1984 Black Media Recommendation (Box 26)
  - African Americans--Radio Usage by Blacks, 1975 (Box 26)
  - African Americans--R.T. French: Reaching the Black Consumer, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Asian Americans--Reaching the Asian-American Market, 1989 (Box 26)
  - Baby Boomers--Baby Boomers in Midpassage, 1987 (Box 26)
  - Baby Boomers--Emerging Superclass, 1981 (Box 26)
  - Baby Boomers--Esperts' Guide to the Baby Boomers, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Baby Boomers--How the Baby Boom Lives, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Baby Boomers--Post-Boomers: A New Breed, 1991 (Box 26)
  - Baby Boomers--The New Old, 1989 (Box 26)
  - Baby Boomers--What Advertisers Are Saying to Reach the Aging Baby Boomers, 1982 (Box 26)
  - Children--Advertising to Children: What We Believe Works, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Children--Advertising to Children: What We Know and What We Should Know, 1978 (Box 27)
  - Children--Children: A Dynamic Media Segment, 1988 (Box 27)
  - Children--Children: The Market with the Most Potential, 1991 (Box 27)
  - Children--Children as a Special Market, 1976 (Box 27)
  - Children--Children as Consumers, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Children--Children as Consumers, 1987 (Box 27)
  - Children--Children, Mothers and Newspapers, 1978 (Box 27)
  - Children--Children's Magazines, 1984 (Box 27)
  - Children--Children's Print Media Opportunities, 1988 (Box 27)
  - Children--Children's Saturday Morning Activities, 1992 (Box 27)
  - Children--Communicating with Children, 1981 (Box 27)
  - Children--Communicating with Children: Getting Your Message to Kids, 1992 (Box 27)
  - Children--Data from Youth Monitor, 1987 (Box 27)
  - Children--Do You Know Where Your Children Are...In the Marketplace?, 1978 (Box 27)
  - Children--Effects of Campaign Advertising and Newscasts on Children, circa 1976 (Box 27)
  - Children--Fisher-Price: Kids' Television Marketplace, 1986 (Box 27)
  - Children--Focus on the Family: A New Way of Looking at Advertising Impact, 1976 (Box 27)
  - Children--Kellogg Company: U.S. Child-Directed Media, 1986 (Box 27)
  - Children--Kids as Consumers, 1989 (Box 27)
  - Children--Kids TV, 1986 (Box 27)
  - Children--Marketing to Kids, 1986 (Box 27)
  - Children--NAB Children's Television Advertising Guidelines, 1976 (Box 27)
  - Children--Nickelodeon Kids Planning Guide, 1998 (Box 27)
  - Children--No Lambs, Bears or Talking Down, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Children--Scott Paper: Saturday Morning Children's Programming, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Children--Self-Regulatory Guidelines for Children's Advertising, 1983 (Box 28)
  - Children--Star Power 2: Understanding Kids and Their Stars, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Children--Sunday Comics, 1988 (Box 28)
  - Children--Television and Children, 1986 (Box 28)
  - Children--The Children's Market: Target Selling, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Children--Today's Children: The New Consumer, 1989 (Box 28)
  - Children--TV Beer Commercials and Children, 1990 (Box 28)
  - Children--What Do We Know About the Children's Market?, 1985 (Box 28)
  - College Age--Benetton 1987 College Media Opportunities (Box 28)
  - College Age--Campus Monitor: College Media Usage and Industry Report, 1988 (Box 28)
  - College Age--College Market and Media Overview, 1986 (Box 28)
  - College Age--College Market Profile of Students as Consumers, 1982 (Box 28)
  - College Age--College Youth: A Social Values Perspective, 1980 (Box 28)
  - College Age--Executive Summary CollegeTrack, 1988 (Box 28)
  - College Age--Kodak Film 1987 College Media Plan, 1986 (Box 28)
  - College Age--Miscellaneous ideas and articles, 1991 (Box 28)
  - College Age--MTV College Scan, 1988 (Box 28)
  - College Age--The College Market (Cosmopolitan), 1987 (Box 28)
  - College Age--Warner-Lambert EPT College Media Recommendation, 1984 (Box 28)
  - Ethnic miscellaneous--Minority Advertising, 1978 (Box 28)
  - Mature/Elderly--Age Differences in Information Processing, 1986 (Box 28)
  - Mature/Elderly--Aging and the Problem of Television Clutter, 1994 (Box 28)
  - Mature/Elderly--American Maturity, 1993 (Box 28)
  - Mature/Elderly--Emotional Truths of the Third Age, 1997 (Box 28)
  - Mature/Elderly--Mature American in the 1990s (Modern Maturity), 1995 (Box 28)
  - Mature/Elderly--Miscellaneous articles and notes, 1997 and undated (Box 28)
  - Mature/Elderly--Promiscuity of Mature Consumers, 1997 (Box 28)
  - Mature/Elderly--Speaking Grey Language, 1997 (Box 28)
  - Spanish--Advertising to the Hispanic Consumer, 1980 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Counting on More than Trust, 1988 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Gerber Baby food: Spanish Media Usage Habits, 1987 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Hispanic Consumer Market Report, 1992 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Hispanic Market (Television/Radio Age), 1985 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Hispanic Media Overview (JWT Hispania), 1988 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Hispanic Opportunity, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Hispanics Are Hot, 1987 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--New Data with New Implications for Targeting Hispanic Americans, 1993 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Nosotros...We...è (U.S. Dept. of Commerce), undated (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Radio Today: The Hispanic Listener, 1985 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Reynolds Wrap Hispanic Market Review and Recommendation, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Spanish USA, 1984 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Spanish USA, 1986 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--U.S. Hispanics: A Market Profile, 1980 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--What Does "Hispanic" Mean?, 1993 (Box 29)
  - Spanish--Yankelovich Update on the Hispanic Market, 1984 (Box 29)
  - Women--2001: A Woman's Odyssey, 1993 (Box 29)
  - Women--Advertising to Women, 1973 (Box 29)
  - Women--Advertising to Women with Different Career Orientations, 1985 (Box 29)
  - Women--Ascent of Woman, 1993 (Box 30)
  - Women--Chameleon Complex, 1986 (Box 30)
  - Women--Empirical Evaluation of the Bartos Model of Wife's Work Involvement, 1993 (Box 30)
  - Women--Gerber Baby Food: Daytime Network Television Viewing, 1987 (Box 30)
  - Women--Mediastyles I: Demographic Profile of Canadian Women and Their Media Habits, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Women--Mediastyles II: Women's Lifestyle and Television Viewing Habits, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Women--Moving Target (Rena Bartos), circa 1974 (Box 30)
  - Women--Relationships Key in Reaching Women, 1997 (Box 30)
  - Women--The Working Woman, 1970 (Box 30)
  - Women--True Story Report on the New Collar Woman, 1989 (Box 30)
  - Women--Two-Income Families, 1981 (Box 30)
  - Women--We, the American Women, 1987 (Box 30)
  - Women--What Every Marketer Should Know About Women (Rena Bartos), 1978 (Box 30)
  - Women--Women and Work, 1986 (Box 30)
  - Women--Women in Transition, 1989 (Box 30)
  - Women--Working-Class Women in a Changing World, 1973 (Box 30)
  - Women--Working Women: Television and Radio, 1986 (Box 30)
  - Women--Working Women: Working Towards a New Balance, 1982 (Box 30)
  - Young adults--Kodak Film 1988 Young Parents Effort Media Discussion, 1987 (Box 30)
  - Young adults--The Next Generation: Today's Young Adults, 1993 (Box 30)
- Oversize Materials, 1965-1973; 5
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Alberto-Culver, 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Avon, 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Breck, 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Clairol, 1965-1966; 3 folders (Box 31)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Colgate-Palmolive (Lustre-Crème), 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--DuBerry (Color Foam), 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Helena Rubinstein, 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Helene Curtis, 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Johnson Johnson (Baby Shampoo), 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--L'Oreal, 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Miscellaneous, 1965-1966, 1972; 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Ogilvie, 1965 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Procter Gamble (Head Shoulders), 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Revlon, 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Richard Hudnut (Lilt, Polycolor), 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Roux Labs, 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Shulton (Technique Color Tone), 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Thomas Scalp Specialists, 1972-1973 (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Hair care--Toni, 1965-1966 (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Kitchen cabinets, 1972 (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Pain remedies--Mentholatum competitors, 1972-1973 (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Alberto-Culver, 1973 (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Arden, 1972 (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Avon, 1973 (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Gillette, 1972-1973 (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Mem (English Leather, Wind Drift), 1972-1973 (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Miscellaneous, 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--North (Norelco), 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Revlon (Pub, Top Brass), 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Ronson, 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Schick, 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Sperry-Rand (Remington), 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Sunbeam, 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Shaving accessories and men's toiletries--Swank (Jade East), 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Dana (Canoe, Pullman), 1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Gillette, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Helena Rubinstein, 1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Jergens, 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Max Factor, 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Menley James (Loves Fresh), 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Miscellaneous bath products, 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Miscellaneous dry Advertisements--Skin creams, 1972-1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Miscellaneous hand lotions, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Miscellaneous moisturizers, 1973 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Miscellaneous Advertisements--Skin cleansers, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Noxema, 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Pfizer (Vick's, Ben-Gay), 1972 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Pond's, 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Skin care and lotions, cosmetics--Revlon, 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Smoking and tobacco products--Cigarettes, 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Smoking and tobacco products--Gillette (Cricket, Braun), 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Smoking and tobacco products--Maruman, 1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Smoking and tobacco products--Rogers lighters, 1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Smoking and tobacco products--Ronson lighters, 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Smoking and tobacco products--Zippo lighters, 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Soap--Andrew Jergens, 1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Soap--Armour (Dial), 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Soap--Campagna (Cuticura), 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Soap--Colgate-Palmolive, 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Soap--Lever (Dove), 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Soap--Miscellaneous, 1972-1973 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Soap--Neutrogena, 1972 (Box 35)
  - Advertisements--Soap--Procter Gamble (Camay), 1972 (Box 35)
  - Contests, 1967 (Box 36)
  - Contests, 1972 (Box 37)
  - Premiums, 1971 (Box 38)
  - Premiums, 1972 (Box 39)
  - Premiums, 1973 (Box 40)
  - Special offers, 1967 (Box 41)
  - Special offers, 1970 (Box 42)
  - Special offers, 1971 (Box 43-44)
  - Special offers, 1972 (Box 45)
  - Special offers, 1973 (Box 46)
- 2018 Additions, 1901-2006 and undated; 1
  - Account Planning, 1965-2006 and undated; 1
    - 112 Years of Brand Leadership, 2003 (Box 47)
    - 133 Years of Advertising Leadership, 1997 (Box 47)
    - Adults 55-74, 2002 (Box 47)
    - Archetypes, 2000-2003; 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Baby boomers, 2003-2004 (Box 52a)
    - Brand essence, 1995-2004 (Box 52a)
    - Brand growth, 2004 (Box 47)
    - Consumer buying system, undated (Box 47)
    - Consumer Insight and Day One, 1994 (Box 47)
    - Consumer insight: Miracle Whip, 1992 (Box 47)
    - Consumer spending, 2003 (Box 47)
    - Cool, 2004 (Box 47)
    - Cool brands, 2002-2003 (Box 47)
    - Coolhunting, 2003 (Box 47)
    - Creative brief writing, 2003 (Box 47)
    - Day One, undated (Box 47)
    - Day One: Seducing the muse, 1995 (Box 47)
    - Day One strategy development and creative briefing process, 1992 (Box 47)
    - Families--Families 2000 (Trends and changes), 2001 (Box 47)
    - Families--Insight Out: The State of the Family in America, 2000 (Box 47)
    - Food--Eating habits, 2002 (Box 47)
    - Food--Flavor factor, 2003 (Box 47)
    - Food--Indulgent snacks, 2002 (Box 48)
    - Food--Seafood Deep Dive, 2006 (Box 52a)
      Scope and Contents
      Restricted until 2021
    - Food--Trends, 2003-2005 (Box 48)
    - Food--What America Eats, 2003 (Box 48)
    - Food--Yankelovich food report, 2002-2004 (Box 48)
    - Gender, 2003 (Box 48)
    - Generations, undated (Box 48)
    - Health and wellness, 2001-2003 (Box 48)
    - Icons, 2003 (Box 48)
    - Icons and mature brands, 1997-2003 (Box 48)
    - Idea generation, undated (Box 48)
    - Indulgence, 2002 (Box 48)
    - James Webb Young--Technique for Producing Ideas, 2003 (Box 48)
    - JWT Planning Toolkit, 2006 (Box 52a)
    - JWT Strategic Plan, 1995-1996 (Box 48)
    - Kraft--SAMI (Selling Areas Marketing Information), 1975 (Box 48)
    - Mindset, 2004 (Box 48)
    - New products, 2000-2004 (Box 48)
    - New products--Word of mouth, 2004 (Box 48)
    - Paradox of Choice, 2004 (Box 48)
    - Persuasion, undated (Box 49)
    - Planning--AAAA Account Planning Conference, 2003 (Box 49)
    - Planning boot camp, 2002 (Box 49)
    - Play, 2003 (Box 49)
    - Power of a Brand Idea: The Philadelphia Story (slides), undated (Box 49)
    - Some World Class Brands Getting to Know Each Other, 2004 (Box 52a)
    - Starch INRA Hooper, 1982 (Box 49)
    - Storytelling, 2003 (Box 49)
    - Stress-driven consumption, 2003 (Box 49)
    - Taglines, 1998 (Box 49)
    - Thompson Total Branding, 1997 and undated; 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Thompson Total Branding--Atlanta, 1996 (Box 49)
    - Thompson Total Branding--Behind the curtain, 1999 (Box 49)
    - Thompson Total Branding--Brand contact planning, 1996 (Box 49)
    - Thompson Total Branding--Branding ideas, undated (Box 49)
    - Thompson Total Branding--Explaining the unexplained, 1996 (Box 49)
    - Thompson Way handbook, undated (Box 49)
    - Thompson Way of Total Branding, 1996 (Box 49)
    - Total branding, 1996 (Box 50)
    - Total branding--Chicago, 1996 (Box 50)
    - Trends, 2003; 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Trends--99 Cows, 2003 (Box 50)
    - Trends--Friction-free future, 1998 (Box 50)
    - Trends--Mega trends, 2003 (Box 50)
    - Trends--Times and trends, 2004 (Box 50)
    - Using media, 2003 (Box 50)
    - Walk the Talk: A Step by Step Approach to Implementing Innovation, 1993 (Box 50)
    - Women--21st century women, 2003 (Box 50)
    - Women--American Women: Key Trends for the Next Decade, 2001 (Box 50)
    - Women--Focus on women, 2001 and undated; 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Women--Moms, 2003 (Box 50)
    - Women--Women: A Transforming Force of the 21st Century, 2001 (Box 50)
    - Women--Women: A Transforming Force of the 21st Century, 2001 (Box 51)
    - Yin and Yang of Consumer Insight (Malachy Walsh), 2002 (Box 51)
    - Youth--17-year old ditz, undated (Box 51)
    - Youth--Advertising to children, 1972 (Box 51)
    - Youth--Advertising to children: background, principles, examples, 1993 (Box 51)
    - Youth--Age segmentation, 1995 (Box 51)
    - Youth--Cassandra Report "Youth Intelligence", 2004 (Box 51)
    - Youth--Fads, trends and timeless needs, 2003 (Box 51)
    - Youth--Generation X/Y, 2000 (Box 51)
    - Youth--Global cool hunt, 2003 (Box 51)
    - Youth--Hip Hop, 2004 (Box 51)
    - Youth--Hot stuff, 1996 (Box 51)
    - Youth--How to Make Successful Advertising to Children, undated; 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Youth--How to Play the Ideation Game with Children, 2000 (Box 51)
    - Youth--How to Win Children and Influence Mother, 1965 (Box 51)
    - Youth--Insight Out: Kids, 2000 (Box 52)
    - Youth--It's the 90s: Do You Know Where the Kids Are?, 1993 (Box 52)
    - Youth--Kid influencers, 2003 (Box 52)
    - Youth--Kid Kraft: Advertising to Children, 1990 (Box 52)
    - Youth--Moms and kids, 2003-2004 (Box 52)
    - Youth--New product development, 1998 (Box 52)
    - Youth--Oscar Mayer and the Delights of Childhood, 1996 (Box 52)
    - Youth--Rethinking Rebellion, 2004 (Box 52)
    - Youth--Selling Food as Fun, 2003 (Box 52)
    - Youth--Teenagers, 2000 (Box 52)
    - Youth--Tweenagers, 2002 (Box 52)
    - Youth--Tweeners, 2003 (Box 52)
    - Youth--Youthfluentials, undated (Box 52)
  - Account Reference Files, 1956-1981; 2
    - FMC Corporation, undated (Box 98)
    - Miles Laboratories, 1962 (Box 53)
    - Parker Pen, 1956-1980 (Box 53)
    - Schlitz, 1978 (Box 53)
    - Seven-Up, 1966-1978 (Box 53)
    - Teledyne Water-Pik, 1977-1981 (Box 53)
    - Tersa (Ward Foods), 1981 (Box 53)
    - Theodore Hamm, 1969-1972 (Box 53)
  - Advertising Awards and Festivals, 1965-2006; 3
    - ACE Awards, 1986 (Box 53)
    - Addy Awards, 1976-1986; 7 folders (Box 53)
    - Advertising Age Best TV Commercials, 1982-1983; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - American TV and Radio Commercials Festival, 1966-1970; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Andy Awards, 1968-1984; 4 folders (Box 54)
    - Andy Awards, 1970-1971 (Box 98)
    - Art Directors Club, 1979-1981; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Atlanta International Film Festival, 1970 (Box 54)
    - Award winners summary, 1979-1984 (Box 54)
    - Awards competition calendar, 1969 (Box 54)
    - CA Magazine Awards, 1967-1970 (Box 54)
    - Chicago, 1974-1979; 6 folders (Box 54)
    - Chicago Addy Awards, 1982-1984; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Chicago Advertising Club Hermes Award, 1967-1970; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Chicago International Film Festival, 1966-1983; 4 folders (Box 54)
    - Clio Awards, 1975-1985; 8 folders (Box 54)
    - Cork (Ireland) Film Festival, 1970 (Box 54)
    - Creativity '84, 1984 (Box 54)
    - CSCA/STA Exhibition, 1965-1970; 2 folders (Box 54)
      Chicago Society of Communication Arts/Society of Typographical Arts
    - Directory of advertising awards (AAAA), 1970 (Box 54)
    - Effie Awards, 1976-1994; 5 folders (Box 54)
    - Effie Awards, 1984-1995; 25 folders (Box 55)
    - Effie Awards, 1995-2006; 18 folders (Box 56)